one of the amazing aspects of my life is
this community that I am part of I have
been involved since the beginning my
child the beginning of my child is very
intertwined in this community at least
in my mind because one of the first
workshops of us planning this community
is right around the time that my child
was conceived and getting to watch this
community come together as people joined
it as decisions were made as the
bureaucracy would stall it and we'd have
to figure out how to deal with internal
conflict and external conflict and it
had shaped my worldview it has helped me
think of ways that everybody can have
access to this level of community I as a
single parent living below the poverty
line with a lot of health challenges I
get to participate in a community that
means that those things have less of an
impact on my child that I get a lot of
amazing food for way less than if I made
it by myself definitely way less energy
and if I made it by myself I could get
connection and community when I'm not
capable of it when I can just like zone
out and be in freeze mode and she can be
running around with other kids being as
loud as they wants in the playroom
learning her own interpersonal conflict
strategies with other kids and going to
the parents we need be that I know other
parents although we all have different
parenting style
all of them are compassionate wonderful
people who I trust to discipline my kid
in the moment right oh maybe don't do
that that's not safe don't do that do
that and often to do it in a better way
than I can even do it especially in
those moments but I'm not capable
because it's loud and chaotic around me
get to eat these amazing meals get to
participate there's aspects that like
they have a yoga room
that I have access to that if I wanted
to I could go up and do yoga in a
private studio three times a week or
more times a week there because they
share that space right for each of them
to have their own yoga studio would be
ridiculous
but the fact that they get to share in
that means that you know a middle-class
families have what upper-class families
would have access to they all have
access to two guest rooms that they they
share access to a kitchen that they can
host larger extended family gatherings
in and then clean up there and don't
have to bring it back to the house right
not have to clean up their house the
brand that they share in child care they
share in like my kid just have this
amazing birthday thanks to community
just because like one of my friends got
us tickets to the aquarium I'm not who
lives in the community and because I got
the tickets to the aquarium one of the
moms covered the the cost of food at the
cafe and so it was basically like I paid
for some souvenir photos so like my kid
had her seventh birthday at the
Vancouver Aquarium for like under fifty
bucks
hurry impromptu you supposed to be just
a small Kathryn but when you have a
small gathering in community and then a
few kids join in adds up like it was
five kids and a day at the aquarium and
that was perfect those kind of things
like last Valentine's Day there was this
amazing fondue for for the kids we had
Apple walking home in a snowstorm
because the buses were running but the
kind of thing that I don't have the
energy or the creativity in that facet
to put on and we you know karaoke events
and things where they had like these
mocktails that like were the different
rainbow rainbow levels right based on
the density of the liquid that they they
made for the kids they were cocktails
none not alcoholic but beautiful and you
know going camping but not having to I
can't go camping just the two of us is
too much work too much executive
functioning but going camping with this
group where you know someone brings it
kayak and someone else is singing around
singing around the camp
or the odd time I get to go in and house
it for somebody there which is amazing
because it's it's we're like the one
person who can go and house it and be
part of the community anyone else that
there's a need like kids are in and out
of our house constantly whichever house
we're staying at because that's what how
life works there they like your kid is
within this somewhat enclosed safe
community not somewhat it is enclosed
and say if they could get out if they
wanted to but people can't get in and
like finding your kid they don't want to
be found a little bit difficult between
these like you have to go knock out
everyone's doors my kid here is my kid
here it's just it's what everyone should
have access to and yet if you didn't
want to live there it's kind of torture
there's a few this is one of the
conversations I was having last night
when we were on a cleanup team together
what is how well families work in this
community because you can have
introverts and extroverts if you're an
introvert you can hang out in your house
most of the time and and and not go out
you can go out and get social
interaction when you need it or want it
and even when you're not like my kid can
go and get social interaction in fact
it's the one place where when we stay
there my kid gets overly socialized like
she gets beyond her socialization point
as an extrovert and needs to kinda have
some down time normally in her life it's
way under that level because we exist at
home the two of us and we have to let go
up to the park and get that social
interaction community I had so much it
adds actual resources for way less money
everyone has a much lower social impact
they're like we're going out this
weekend one of the people is the
designated driver cuz she doesn't drink
but she's using one of the other women's
cars because she has a seven-seater car
we've got brought our kids to sleepaway
camp during the summer and it was three
of our kids going the three moms all dry
bean and we all got to fit in the same
vehicle including one of the little
sisters he wasn't going and those kind
of things just pop up constantly and I'm
just so grateful to have these people in
my life and get to see the impact of
community and I want everyone
have access to this I want this to not
be a scarce resource where everyone can
have common meals and get to eat
together as a community everyone can
know that that they know their neighbors
and how do we create that we're gonna
figure it out but also creating
intentional communities from the ground
up not creating them for profit and
creating them for purpose instead but
this is my video on my community thank
you